Guide to the Weaver Social History Collection, 1913-1970 AIS.1964.19
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Assorted Publications and Materials, 1930-1970; VIII.
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 36)
    Numerous pamphlets on nuclear war, disarmament, peace activism, Soviet Union, newspaper clippings
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 37)
    Fellowship, Peace Action, numerous pamphlets and journals on nuclear war, peace, newspaper clippings
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 38)
    Numerous pamphlets on religion, social issues, and newspaper clippings
  - Assorted Publications, 1950-1960 (Box 39)
    Journals and publications on steel industry, unions, strikes, and labor
  - Assorted Publications, 1950-1960 (Box 40)
    Arts and entertainment in Pittsburgh newspaper clippings, newsletters, journals, pamphlets
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 41)
    Scriber's Commentator; Information Service; The Standard; Friday
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 42)
    The Pittsburgh Daily Reporter,
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1960 (Box 43)
    Town Crier; University of Pittsburgh Graduation Bulletin
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1950 (Box 44)
    Newspaper clippings on WWII, U.S. Policies, World News, Economics, Politics
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 45)
    The Bulletin Index
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1960 (Box 46)
    Freedom and Union
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 47)
    Numerous pamphlets on America First Committee, anti-war movement, WWII, Charles Lindbergh
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1970 (Box 48)
    The Freeman; numerous pamphlets, newspaper clippings
  - Assorted Publications, 1950-1970 (Box 49)
    Numerous pamphlets on commerce, economics, politics, newspaper clippings
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1960 (Box 50)
    Weekly Shopper, newspaper clippings on Soviet Union, anti-war nuclear disarmament
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1960 (Box 51)
    Numerous pamphlets and newspaper clippings on urban planning in Pittsburgh, subway sewage, new
  - Assorted Publications, 1920-1950 (Box 52)
    The Survey; Time; Homewood Brushton News; Weekly People; Collier's The National Weekly; Survey Graphic
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1970 (Box 53)
    Newsletters, journals, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets on religion, social issues, and education
  - Assorted Publications, 1920-1950 (Box 54)
    Fellowship; The Christian Century; The Reporter
  - Assorted Publications, 1920, 1950 (Box 55)
    Jewish Pictorial Leader; New America, correspondence, letters, newspaper clippings and pamphlets on League of Nations, Wilson's 14 points, War, Conscription, Nuclear War
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 56)
    The Attendant: A Civic Clinic for Better Living by Allegheny Conference on Community Development, journals and newsletters on WWII, Aid to Allies, Aid to England, religion, Pittsburgh politics, local government
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 57)
    Note cards with names and addresses of Fellowship of Reconciliation members, speaker note cards, social issues
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 58)
    Causes and Effect: Municipal Record, correspondence, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and books on business, economics, Pittsburgh City Council
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1950 (Box 59)
    Various publications on politics, world news, communism in Latin America, Urban planning in Pittsburgh
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 60)
    The World Tomorrow; UNA News; Peace Action; World Alliance Newsletter
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1950 (Box 61)
    Correspondence and reports on Pittsburgh Public Schools, Allegheny County Taxes, politics in the City of Pittsburgh
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1950; Fellowship; pamphlets, envelopes (Box 62)
    Fellowship; pamphlets, envelopes
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 63)
    March of Progress, subject files on politics, world events, economics, and social issues
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 64)
    Henry George News; correspondence, reports, books, and newsletters on politics, economics, world news
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 65)
    Various publications on politics, socialism, world news, post-WWII Europe, Pittsburgh business, electric, steel
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1970; New York Times coverage of JFK Assassination; Allegheny Round table (Box 66)
    New York Times coverage of JFK Assassination; Allegheny Roundtable
  - Assorted Publications, 1960-1980 (Box 67)
    Various publication on economics, animals, Allegheny Roundtable
  - Assorted Publications, 1960-1980 (Box 68)
    Reports, photos, newsletters, pamphlets, various publication on Friends Committee on National Legislation, ART Financial records, photographs of politics in Pittsburgh
  - Assorted Publications, 1960-1980 (Box 69)
    New York Times coverage of LBJ, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, reports, newsletters on Vietnam, abortion, alternative education, civic club, Skybus, and transportation
  - Assorted Publications, 1970-1980 (Box 70)
    Newspaper clippings, newsletters, and correspondence on George McGovern campaign
  - Assorted Publications, 1960-1980 (Box 71)
    Fellowship; newspaper clippings, journals, newsletters, and books on Anti-war movement, disarmament, draft, and Vietnam
  - Assorted Publications, 1960-1980 (Box 72)
    Newsletters, newspaper clippings, correspondence, subject files on Japan, Czech Republic, India, Soviet Union, and Vietnam
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1970 (Box 73)
    Correspondence and pamphlets related to Europe, racial issues, 1960s, Britain, and U.S. Economic Policy
  - Assorted Publications, 1950-1970 (Box 74)
    Correspondence and pamphlets related to Vietnam, pacifism, labor
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1950 (Box 75)
    Personal correspondence, note cards with names and addresses
  - Assorted Publications, 1920-1960 (Box 76)
    Personal correspondence to groups and schools organized by subject
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 77)
    Friends Committee on National Legislation; American Friends Service Committee; Steel Facts. Correspondence and pamphlets on Allegheny Roundtable, labor, politics, world news
  - Assorted Publications (Box 78)
    American Friends Service Committee; Council Against Communist Aggression. Note cards on various subjects
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 79)
    Pittsburgh Personnel Association; Correspondence to clubs and schools in subject order
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 80)
    American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence to schools
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 81)
    East Liberty Tribune; The Christian Advocate. Newspaper clippings and pamphlets relating to peace activism before and after WWII, temperance movement, U.S. foreign policy, education, and economics
  - Assorted Publications, 19402-1950 (Box 82)
    The CIO News; Pennsylvania Federalist; Interpreting the Labor News; Analysis. Newsletters, reports, pamphlets, newspapers relating to civil rights, world news, and Martin Luther King, Jr.
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1960 (Box 83)
    Colonial Supply Co; industrial catalog. Books and scrapbooks relating to juvenile delinquency, peace activism in Europe, World News, index cards
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1970 (Box 84)
    Slavic Review; World Politics; Midwest Journal of Political Science Review; Graphic; Survey; The Atlantic; The Voice of Austria. Books relating to Europe and politics
  - Assorted Publications, 1934, 1960 (Box 85)
    World Politics; Midwest Journal of Political Science Review; Monthly Review
  - Assorted Publications, 1960-1970 (Box 86)
    Slovakia; Slavic Review; World Politics; International Affairs; Minvera
  - Assorted Publications, 1940-1960 (Box 87)
    Correspondence, note cards, and subject files
  - Assorted Publications, 1930-1970 (Box 88)
- Allegheny Roundtable, 1948-1970; IX.
  In the late 1940s John C. Weaver help found the Allegheny Roundtable, a panel discussion program that aired on WQED radio and later became a WQED television program. The Allegheny Roundtable resembled the Hungry Club, as it was a forum to discuss affairs in Pittsburgh and world news. His status in Pittsburgh was heightened during the 1960s because of his opinions of the steel industry, unemployment, and the Vietnam War. The Allegheny Roundtable contains correspondence of the organization and is unprocessed. The material dates from 1948 to 1970.
  - Correspondence, 1948-1970 (Box 89-104)